# Robertson Lovell McClure

May 3rd, 2016

(647) 229-4608

R.McClure@mail.utoronto.ca https://robertsonmcclure.github.io

I am a third year student-athlete at the University of Toronto pursuing a Major in Mathematics and a Specialist's Degree in Computer Science. I am employed full-time by StockRender as a software developer and employed by the University of Toronto part-time to develop software solutions for the Strength & Conditioning Department for Varsity Athletics. When I'm not being paid to develop software, I'm studying for two summer school courses at UofT in software development. Any free time is typically spent reading books on programming, working out and enjoying life.

# Skills

Python Java C HTML/CSS JavaScript SVN Git Vim

# **Employment**

**Software Developer** 

StockRender

Summer of 2016

• Develop an API for the terminal, a product StockRender sells to hedge funds.

**Sports Analytics Developer** 

**UofT Strength & Conditioning** Summer of 2016

• Create a database to store Strength Data and automate the processing of daily survey results

**Head Referee / Convener** 

**UofT Intramural Volleyball** 

**2015 - Present** 

• Hire, train and schedule volleyball officials for the 10+ matches that occur every weekday

**Recruiting Assistant** 

**UofT Mens Volleyball** 

2015 - Present

• Facilitate campus tours to potential recruits, communicate with all athletes who are interested in being recruited and assist recruits in navigating UofT's application process

Statistician

**UofT Mens Volleyball** 

**2014 - Present** 

Scout opponents using Data Project Software and report in-game statistics to coaching staff

**Certified Volleyball Official** 

Ontario Volleyball Association

**2012 - Present** 

- Ensure that match play occurs in accordance to Volleyball Canada Rules
- Apply interpretation of rules to in-game scenarios

**Mathematics Tutor** 

**Self-Employed** 

2014 - 2015

- Teach first year calculus and linear algebra in a comprehensive manner
- Create individualized lesson plan for each student to cater to their needs

Counsellor

Camp Tawingo

2013 - 2015

- Responsible for 8 ten year old boys at over night camp for their three week stay
- Organize themed programs and games for campers

# Volunteer Positions

# Website Administrator & Videographer The Reading Line

**2015 - Present** 

- Update TheReadingLine.ca and design the user experience as the web-traffic increases
- Create promotional videos, which includes directing, producing, filming and editing.

## Sitting Volleyball Data Entry Volunteer Parapan American Games Summer of 2015

• Use volleyball terminology to translate the game into live statistics in a fast paced environment

# Volleyball Data Entry Volunteer Pan American Games Summer of 2015

• Use volleyball terminology to translate the game into live statistics in a fast paced environment

# Creative Director 100in1day | Slow Down Jane Summer of 2015

- Create promotional videos, which includes directing, producing, filming and editing.
- Advise on outreach plans to local communities

# **Elected Positions**

### **Athlete and Team Manager**

### **UofT Mens Volleyball**

**2014 - Present** 

- Commit over two hours every day to the team
- Responsible for the team's equipment including the camera, food supplements, etc.
- Prompt execution of miscellaneous jobs at the discretion of the Head Coach

#### **Gate House President**

## Victoria College

2015 - Present

- Organize social events including a Pub Night and Traditional Ceremonies
- Represent the needs of Gate House at the Building Council Meetings

#### **Math Union Treasurer**

## **University of Toronto**

2015 - Present

- Responsible for the allocation of funds and balancing the budget
- Reimburse Math Union members for approved purchases and manage the bank account

#### **Math Union Social Officer**

#### **University of Toronto**

2014 - 2015

- Organize catered social events in conjuncture with other unions
- Responsible for acquiring and transporting food to and from the venue

#### **Athletic Representative**

#### **Gate House Council**

2014 - 2015

- Advertise Varsity Athletics to Gate House
- · Assist in organizing athletic events for Gate House Members

#### **Athletic Banquet Coordinator**

#### **UTS Athletics**

2014

- Organize a 3 hour catered award event that featured multiple key note speakers
- Master of Ceremonies

## Volleyball Coach

#### **UTS Athletics**

2011 - 2014

• Plan practices, coach volleyball and travel with the team to tournaments

# Education

B.Sc. Math B.Sc. Computer Science Ontario Secondary School Diploma  Awards	University of Toronto University of Toronto University of Toronto Schools	Class of 2019 Class of 2019 Class of 2014
Dean's Leadership Scholar Award	Faculty of Kinesiology	2016
Professor R. K. Arnold Scholarship Regents Admissions Scholarship Presidents Entrance Scholarship	Victoria University Victoria University University of Toronto	2015 2014 2014
University of Toronto Schools Diploma Ontario Scholar	University of Toronto Schools University of Toronto Schools	2014 2014